Against this foe,
there shall be no playing by ear!
(自来也)コイツを相手に
様子見はない！
I'm coming at you with full force!
最初から全力でいくからのぉ！
(自来也)仙人モードを使う！
I'm using the Honored Sage Mode!
What?! You don't mean...?!
(ガマケン)まさか！ では…。
Yes indeed.
そのまさか。
あの二大仙人を口寄せする。
I'm summoning the two great sages!
だが あの２人を呼ぶまで
ちっとばかり時間がかかる。
However, it's going to take some time
to summon the two of them.
その間
この手を離すことはできん。
And I cannot release my hands
during that time.
I'm counting on you.
Buy me some time until then!
頼む！ それまで
時間を稼いでくれ！
わかった。
不器用なりにやってみよう。
All right. Clumsy as I am, I shall try.
消えおったか。 厄介だの。
He vanished. What a bother...
Where in the world did he find
such a creature?
どこで見つけてきたんだ
あんなのを。
Now that he's made himself invisible,
we've got to use Barrier Battle Arts.
消えたとあっては
結界戦術でやるしかないの。
Hmm... He's a hard one to battle.
う～む！ 戦いにくいな。
(ペイン)確か あれは➡
As I recall...
This is a barrier ninjutsu that senses and
alerts any intrusion across its boundary.
足を踏み入れたら
感知するタイプの結界忍術。
ならば…。
In that case...
結界を見て
攻撃力の強いのに変えてきたか！
He saw the barrier and switched
to a strong offensive critter!
Gamaken-san!
ガマケンさん！
おう！ 不器用ながら➡
Right! Clumsy as I am, here we go!
お控えなすってもらいやす！
You're quite skilled!
器用じゃねえか。
(ガマケン)いえいえ。
Not at all... I am clumsy.
自分は 不器用なもんで…。
なに!?
What?!
Wh-What is this?!
な… なんじゃ こりゃ!?
うわっ！
うっ！
Are you okay, Gamaken-san?
(自来也)大丈夫か？ ガマケンさん。
You think you could do this
a bit smoother?
できれば もう少し
うまくやれんもんかの？
But I am clumsy...
自分 不器用なもんで…。
コイツら 殴るたびに増えとるの。
They seem to multiply each time
you clobber them...
もはや 何ものかすら わからん。
I don't even have a clue what it is...
Are the doggies bound to
a self-replicating summoning jutsu?!
自ら 増幅口寄せの術に縛られた
ワン公か？
In any case,
we'd better move from this spot.
(自来也)とにかく
いったん 場を変えんと…。
１匹ずつ 殺る。
狭い場所に誘いこむぞ！
We'll kill one dog at a time!
Let's lure them into a small space.
Right!
おう！
《ペイン : どうやら 術の肝はあれか》
So that's the center of the jutsu...
まいた… かのぉ？
Were we able to lose it...?
That should buy us some time.
時間は稼… げんか！
Or not!
もう 挟まれてしもうた。
We're surrounded already!
来る！ また バラけるぞ。
Incoming! And they're going
to split up again!
上だ！
Above you!
(自来也)これじゃ
きりがないのぉ…。
There's no end to this.
I am  trying my best...
(ガマケン)がんばっては
いるんですがね…。
If they keep dividing,
no matter how hard we strike them,
叩いても 叩いても
無尽蔵に分裂するんじゃ➡
it's a waste of our energy.
努力のしがいがないのぉ…。
Here already?
Damn persistent dogs!
もう 来よったか
このワンパターンめが！
Stupid little...!
この～！
大丈夫かのぉ!? あっ！
Are you all right?!
Gamaken-san!
ガマケンさん！
やっぱり
自分 不器用ですから…。
I really am...
clumsy...
ガマケンさんが動けないんではのぉ…。
If you can't move, Gamaken-san...
then there's no time to summon
the two great sages.
二大仙人様を呼んどる暇はないか。
お手上げじゃ。
I give up.
しかし よくも
これだけ 増えたものよ。 フフフ…。
But I'm amazed
there're so many of them...
だが 妙木山の大蝦蟇にかかりゃ
これくらい ひと飲みよ！
But against the Great Toad
of Mount Myoboku,
you're all nothing but a small snack!
i realise the screaming pain
hearing loud in my brain
but i'm going straight ahead with the scar
I should just get over it and I should just stop feeling it
wasurete shimaeba ii yo kanjinaku nacchaeba ii
and so I covered my grazed heart
surimuita kokoro ni futa wo shitan da
I don't care if I'm hurt 'cause I don't feel pain anymore
kizutsuitatte heki da yo mou itami wa nai kara ne
all while you limped on while dragging your feet behind you
sono ashi wo hikizuri nagara mo
I had lost sight of myself
miushinatta jibun jishin ga
which had crumbled loudly to the ground
oto wo taete kuzureteita
but then I realised it was just the sound of the wind...
kizukeba kaze no oto dake ga
I came here to tell you something following my deep scars
tsutae ni kita yo kizuato wo tadotte
before I am completely crushed by this vast world
sekai ni oshitsubusarete shimau mae ni
do you remember that sky of tears
oboeteru kana namida no sora wo
that pain protected you for me
ano itami ga kimi no koto wo mamotte kureta
that pain is always protecting you
sono itami ga itsumo kimi wo mamotterunda
can you hear me so am i
Honored Sage Mode!
消えた。
犬もろとも ひとまず逃げたか。
Gone... Along with the dogs.
(自来也)逃げとりゃせん！
So he's escaped for now.
I haven't escaped!
長門 まだ詰めが甘いのぉ。
Nagato, you're still a novice.
後ろをとられるとはな！
Leaving your back open for an attack!
お前も影分身か！
You're a Shadow Clone too?!
そう それだけじゃない。
同時に… 口寄せ！
Yes, but that's not all.
At the same time... Summoning Jutsu!
しまった!!
Damn it!
《ダメか…》
It's no good...
ガマケンさん！
Gamaken-san!
なんじゃ？
What?
おっとっと…。
Whoa...
どわっ!!
しめた！
Yes!
お役御免！
You're relieved from duty!
やったわい… えっ？
I did it!
Huh?
《よくも まあ 次から次へと…。
It's one thing after another...
だが もうちょっとだ。
But I'm almost there.
じゃから ここで
やめるわけにはいかんのだが…。
So I can't quit now, but...
来よった！》
Incoming!
なっ… 速い！
Wha--?! So fast!
すまんのぉ。 遅くなった。
Sorry I'm late.
お疲れさん。
Good work!
ハア… ハア… ハア…。
まったく 術者を攻撃しようにも
消えてしまっては手が出せん。
I want to attack the caster,
but I need to be able to see him!
ガマケンさんは
何かおかしいとは思わんか？
Don't you think something
is strange, Gamaken-san?
じ… 自分… 不器用なもんで
よくわからんですが…。
I-I am...
too clumsy to understand
what you mean.
六道仙人と
同じ目を持っていたあヤツは➡
He who possessed the same pupils
as the Sage of the Six Paths,
教えた術を
すべてマスターしたどころか➡
not only mastered every jutsu
I taught him...
１人では
本来ありえぬ チャクラの性質変化。
he demonstrated the ability to achieve
all six changes in Chakra Nature.
６通りの
すべてをやって見せた。
For a single person to do so
is unheard of.
主流忍術すべてに
精通した力を持ち➡
He was well versed in
all the mainstream ninjutsu...
10歳にして
あらゆる術を使いこなした。
and mastered them by the time
he was ten years old.
《なのになぜ…》
But why...?
《なぜ口寄せの術しか
使ってこない？
Why is he only using
the Summoning Jutsu against me?!
自分が
戦うまでもないということか？》
Does he think I am beneath
the need for direct confrontation?
クッ！
ガマケンさん もう大丈夫だ！
Gamaken-san! You've done enough!
I've got it from here, go home!
あとはわしがやる！ 戻ってくれ！
わかった すまぬ。
All right. Thanks.
(シマ)小僧 おぬしゃ 何でこが～な
騒がしいとこば～にしか➡
Lad! Why do you always summon us
in such touchy situations like this?!
口寄せせんのじゃ。
ブン太が怒るのも
無理ねえわいそりゃ。
It's no wonder Bunta gets so mad!
(フカサク)
アハハハッ そう言うなや母ちゃん。
Aw c'mon, Ma.
Naturally, Jiraiya-chan has his reasons.
自来也ちゃんにも
事情いうのがあらな～や。
そりゃ…。
父ちゃんは黙っときんさい！
まったくもう！
お久しぶりにこんなんで➡
You be quiet, Pa!
申し訳ありませんのぉ。
頭に ねえさん。
It's been a while,
and I do apologize for calling you
under these circumstances, Boss, Ma'am.
しっかし小僧 おぬしは
女子にモテんなるいうて➡
But lad... I thought you said
you hated that form,
その体を
嫌がっとったんじゃろうがの。
saying it would make you unpopular
with the ladies!
そうも言って
られなくなりましてのぉ。
I can't afford to be particular right now.
なにせ相手が輪廻眼でして。
After all, my foe has the Rinnegan.
おお 六道の眼か。
Ah... the Pupils of Six Paths?!
ホンマにおったんかいな そんなんが。
Someone actually possesses
such an eye?
まあ それなら仕方もなかろうが。
Well then, you had no choice.
(フカサク)そろそろ１人で
仙人モードに変身できるように➡
You gotta start being able to go into
Sage Mode by yourself, Jiraiya-chan.
なれんといけんで 自来也ちゃん。
お二人に比べたら
まだまだペーペーですんでのぉ。
Compared to you,
I'm still just a novice.
どうか少しの間 お力添えを。
So please lend me your aid
for just a little while...
では いきますぞ。
Shall we begin?
《あれほど苦労して
呼び出したのが あのガマ２匹。
He went through all that just
to summon those two toads...?
いや先生自身に変化が起きている。
No, there is a transformation going on
in Sensei himself.
フン。 大蛇丸にしろ自来也にしろ➡
Humph, whether it's Orochimaru or Jiraiya,
the Sannin each have unique powers.
三忍は 独特の力を使うな》
(フカサク)で どこにおるんなら？
その六道の眼は。
And? Where is the one with
the Pupils of Six Paths?
(シマ)
歳で目がわるうなっとるけんのぉ。
Your eyes must be degrading with age.
いや 透明化する
口寄せ動物のなかに入って➡
No. He's hidden himself inside
a summoning creature
姿を隠しております。
that can make itself invisible.
だとすると
カメレオン類のヤツらじゃのぉ。
It's gotta be one of them
chameleon species.
一応 探知結界は
張っとるんですがのぉ。
I have erected a probe barrier.
そんなんでは ラチがあかん！
生物探知でこっちから
一気に引きずり出しちゃる！
That won't do any good!
Let's drag them out using
creature detection jutsu!
母ちゃん
そうあんまり力入れんなや。
Ma, don't get so excited,
you'll get more wrinkles.
また小ジワが増えるで。
父ちゃんは黙っときんさい！
しかし わしらを
呼んでまで何でそがなヤツと➡
Just hush up, Pa!
But why go so far as to summon us
to fight this fellow, Jiraiya-chan?
自来也ちゃんが
やりあわにゃいけんのなら？
わしのかつての教え子でしてのぉ。
He happens to be
a former student of mine...
そんなヤツがおったとは
聞いとらんぞ！
We never knew you had one!
Then is he...?
ほんなら ソイツも…。
そう…。
Yes...
((自来也 : お呼びで？
(大ジジ様)ほほぉ
よう来た よう来た。
As summoned.
Ah, good. I'm glad you've come!
自来也ちゃんよ 大ジジ様は
お前の夢を見られたんじゃ。
Jiraiya-chan.
The Great Lord Elder had
a dream about you.
お前も知ってのとおり
これは予言じゃ。
As you are aware, it is a prophecy.
心して聞け。
はい。
So listen carefully.
では 伝える。
わしの夢では エロいだけのお主も➡
Yes, sir!
I shall now tell you. In my dream...
いずれ 立派な忍になる。
You, who are solely pervy, will still
manage to become a splendid ninja.
そして 一人前に
弟子を持つことになるのじゃが➡
And in time, you will have
your own disciple...
その弟子は 将来 忍の世に
大きな変革をもたらす忍になる。
That disciple will become a ninja
who will bring about a great change
to the ninja world.
夢では そう見えた。
変革？
That is what I saw in my dream.
世に それまでにない
安定をもたらすか➡
A great change?
Either great stability or great destruction.
(破滅をもたらすか…
そのどちらかの変革じゃ))
The likes of which this world
has never seen before.
One of those two.
予言の子か！
なら なんで お前が戦う!?
The child of the prophecy?!
Then why are you fighting him?
どうやら 正しい方向には
成長しなかったようでしての。
It seems he did not grow up
in the right direction.
それに… すでに 死んだ と
聞かされてまして…。
And when I heard he had died...
この子ではない と
思い込んでました。
I thought he couldn't have been
the one.
どちらにしろ 正しくなけりゃ
殺さにゃいけん。
In any case, if he is not righteous,
you must kill him.
まぁ あの予言は
大ボケジジイの戯れ言じゃ。
Well, that senile old man probably
made up that prophecy.
気にするな！ ほんなら いくで！
Don't worry about it!
All right let's do it!
見つけたで！
Found him!
速い！
It's fast!
捕まえたで！
Gotcha!
とりゃっ！
There we go!
父ちゃん！
おう！
Pa!
I'm on it!
あれが 輪廻眼か。
That's the Rinnegan?
たしかに 伝説に聞く眼と
同じじゃのう。
It certainly looks like the one mentioned
in the legend.
(フカサク)イヤな眼じゃ。
この子が あの予言の子だとはの。
What nasty eyes...
I can't believe he's that child of prophecy.
((大ジジ様 : お主は
その変革者を導く者じゃ。
You will guide that revolutionary.
いずれ お主には 大きな選択を
迫られるときがくるじゃろう。
The day will come when you will be forced
to make a critical selection.
選択？
その選択次第で
世の変革が どちらに転ぶか➡
Selection?
Your choice shall decide which way
the change goes.
(決まってしまうのじゃ))
《ガマ仙人よ… まさしく これが
選択のときですかの》
Great Lord Elder...
I wonder if this is
that moment of selection?
口寄せの術。
Summoning Jutsu.
《今度は 人間の口寄せか》
This time he's summoned humans.
お前は破滅をもたらす者だった。
You turned out to be
a harbinger of destruction...
ならば ここで倒すのが
師の役目だのぉ。
So as your mentor,
it is my duty to take you down!
you are next to me
omae ga tonari ni iru
you are laughing
omae ga waratte iru
you seem so happy
omae ga ureshisou de
so I laughed too
ore mo waratta
you were so innocent and naive
omae wa mujaki datta
you were so kindhearted
omae wa yasashi katta
you sometimes cried
omae wa tokidoki naki
so I was troubled
ore wa komatta
who did I ask strength from at that time
dare yori tsuyosa wo motometa ano koro
since that was my one and only weakness
ore no tatta hitotsu no yowasa ga
that was you
omae datta
and it was you
omae datta n da
I want to see you
aitai
overnights
yoru wo koete
over time
toki wo koete
I want to see you now
ima aitai
(エルザ)私は
仲間を守れる力があれば➡
Next Episode
それだけでいい。
Those three...
They may look different,
but they all have the same eyes.
その力と引き換えならば➡
Even if Nagato is one of the three,
私は 誰より弱くていい。
I can't believe there'd be that
many Rinnegan running about.
矛盾… してるな。
So what in the world's going on?!
(アズマ)おもしろいヤツだ。
There must be
some explanation for this.
お前とは
正々堂々やりたかったね。
Who and what is Pain?!
どういう意味だ？
Next time: "In Attendance, the Six Paths of Pain"
時間切れということさ。
Pay close attention to my battle!
In Attendance, the Six Paths of Pain